Boom!
At the buzzer, Wayne "Captain Clutch"
Rigsby nails the 3.
And the crowd goes insane.
I hate the night shift.
Hey, Jane. Teach me
a card trick, will ya?
Card trick?
- Say, "pick a card".
- Okay.
Pick a card.
Okay.
Put it back in the deck.
Place the deck very gently
on your forehead.
Now try to visualize
the card that I picked, hmm?
Just focus and see it.
- What springs to mind?
- Um, the, uh...
- What card do you see?
- Nine of hearts.
Nine of hearts.
Oh.
- That it?
- Huh. How'd I do that?
Very good.
Very, very good.
- Let me try.
- All right.
Pick a card.
Now...
memorize it.
- Jack of diamonds.
- Nope.
Mm?
- Are you sure?
- Yep.
- Well, uh, Cho...
- It's a card trick. Not interested.
- Well, I guess card tricks are lame.
-Yep, when they don't work.
We're up.
What do you think, doc?
Your basic blunt force trauma.
Baseball bat type of deal.
- Mugging gone wrong, maybe?
- Don't think so.
His wallet's gone
but he did have this on him.
It was wrapped in a napkin
with a note written on it.
Eh, the mysterious case
of the jilted jockey.
Don't be flippant.
- You think he's a jockey?
- Oh, I know he is.
- Why, because he's small?
- Small, bowlegged...
Hungry-thin
in a thousand dollar jacket
deep tan from working outdoors
raccoon eyes
from wearing goggles.
And that is a horseshoe on that napkin
probably from a-a bar in town
that has "horseshoe" in the name.
Well, he could be
a racecar driver.
Racecar drivers have soft hands.
Why a jilted jockey?
Because it alliterates it
and that is always a little fun.
And who else but a forsaken lover
would ask for forgiveness
on a cocktail napkin?
With a ring, no less.
Golden Horseshoe Restaurant
about a mile away.
- "Here you go."
- Sorry, agents, wait.
I just found this
in John Doe's jacket pockets.
I don't know why
I didn't notice it before.
Thanks.
I figure it's some kinda message
maybe from the killer.
That's my card.
How did you do that?
Huh? What?
Card tricks?
A man has lost his life.
You should be ashamed
of yourself.
- Shame.
- Never mind.
Shame. Shame.
So shameful. Terrible.
Flashy clothes about 5'5",
skinny...
like maybe
he could be a jockey.
Sounds like Bill Button.
No, it's... Sutton.
That's the name.
He used to date Delinda...
girl who works here
as a hostess.
He came in last night
looking for her
had a couple of drinks.
Tried to leave something for her
but I told him I couldn't accept it.
Policy.
Did you see what it was?
Yeah. It was a ring
with a note on a napkin.
"Forgive me".
Forgive him for what?
Do you know?
Men. It was always something.
- So what's happened to him?
- Well, he's dead.
The girlfriend... Delinda.
What's her full name?
Um...
It's... Lecure.
Delinda Lecure.
She wasn't working
last night?
No. He... he kept...
coming in, hassling her
to get back together with him.
So she started switching shifts
to avoid him.
He get heavy with her?
Physical.
No. No, no. He was always
a gentleman... what I saw.
But I-I stay out of that stuff.
You know...
- TMI.
- She have any other boyfriends?
Anyone else interested?
Not that I know of.
- You have an address for Delinda?
- Yeah, I-I got it here somewhere.
Cho and Rigsby are talking
to the ex-girlfriend, Delinda, now.
Anything else on the victim?
A William Q. Sutton
is scheduled to ride a horse
in for fifth race
at Redwood Downs today.
- So he is a jockey.
- Yep.
Riding for a man
named Cobb Holwell.
Jane, we're going to Redwood Downs.
Yeah, yeah, you were right.
He's a jockey.
- You coming or not?
- I grew up around horses.
Fine. You can drive.
I'll meet you out there.
- I could come with.
- See what you can find out
about this Cobb Holwell, okay?
Why does horse manure
smell so good?
It doesn't.
Excuse me.
You seen Cobb Holwell
around here?
You're here about Bill, huh?
Yeah. We're with the CBI.
We just have a couple questions.
- And you are...
- Sam Starks.
I'm an apprentice for Mr. Holwell.
Nice animal.
What's his name?
Castor's Folly.
Ah, yes. Castor's Folly.
Sutton was gonna ride him
in the fifth race.
Bill was so good with Cass.
They had a deep bond.
Poor soul.
- He's grieving deeply.
- Aw.
How do you know that?
He knew something was wrong
so I told him.
Okay.
What happened to Bill?
No idea yet.
What's your guess?
I don't know.
You think Cass might have
some kind of idea?
Because we're pretty sure
Mr. Sutton's death
had something to do with horses.
Excuse me.
Cass has to finish his ride.
You can find Mr. Holwell's stables
over there to the left.
Nice.
Teasing a grieving girl.
Prodding, not teasing.
She could be the culprit...
fiendish killer for all we know.
"Hell of a thing."
"Bill was a good man."
- "A good jock."
- Mr. Holwell
uh, did Sutton have
any problems with anyone here?
No. Well liked.
How about women?
Nothing I heard about.
- Well, how long did he...
- Could he have won?
Castor's Folly in the fifth race...
did he have any chance
of winning?
Always.
There's always a chance.
Cass broke his maiden
by three lengths.
Some problems since
but he's finding his form.
He coulda won.
Damn it. He woulda won.
Uh, never mind.
There'll be another race.
We'll find another jock.
- How long did he work for you?
- About three weeks.
- That's all?
- Oh, I'd known Bill for years.
He'd been out of the game
for a while.
When he came back
I hired him but quick.
Gave him 20 grand to ride
for me exclusive.
One final question...
where were you last night?
- Here at the stable.
- All night?
Ma'am, I am
the last independent stable
in this part of the state.
I got one decent horse
and a hundred creditors.
I don't sleep much.
Jane, do you have any... questions.
Thanks for your time.
Black blizzard in the sixth.
It's a lock, trust me.
And where's that tip from?
Somebody who knows.
What are you, a race track cop?
Does it seem legit?
He's a groom at the track stable.
Sounds pretty good.
He works around horses.
I guess he might know something.
You betcha.
I got all the inside poop.
20 bucks buys you a lock
in the 6th. A lock.
How much you betting?
Well, you said it's a lock.
How much are you betting?
All that poop inside, and you're outside
hustling for lunch money, huh?
I'm trying to make a living
here, guy.
- Move right along, why don't ya?
- You used to ride, didn't ya?
Did you... did you know Bill Sutton?
So you are a cop.
You don't look like one.
Yeah, I knew Sutton, and I'll say it
even though he's dead.
He was a lowdown cheat.
Now walk away, pal. I'm trying
to work with my friend here.
Save your money. I'm a better judge
of horses than mister, uh...
Ellis Barnes. Screw you.
Patrick Jane.
Nice to meet you, too.
I will bet you that I can pick
first, second, and third horse
any race you choose, Mr. Barnes
and you're my witness.
Next race.
500 bucks says you can't.
See you at the pay-out window
after the race.
Delinda Lecure, apartment 28.
Why would anyone date
a jockey?
Hungry little guy
smells like horses.
Don't like horses?
They're like dogs but bigger.
You don't like dogs?
It's all an act with dogs.
They do it for the food.
Everybody does.
That's deep.
Ma'am?
"We're from the California Bureau
of Investigation"
and we'd like to...
Excuse me, ma'am.
Do you live here?
Oh, no, not today!
Hello?
This is so ridiculous.
- I don't understand.
- Take it easy.
Hey, just get off me! Okay?
I have my rights.
Hey, this is police brutality!
- What are you gonna do?
- Hey!
- Hey, what's going on?
- Hey, uh... Can you get me a lawyer?
I kinda got this bench warrant
thing out on me.
What bench warrant? We wanna
talk to you about your boyfriend.
- What boyfriend?
- What bench warrant?
Wait, are you talking
about Brandon?
- 'Cause he is not my boyfriend.
- Are you Delinda Lecure?
Nuh-unh. She is.
Okay, who are you people?
Where have you been?
Here, there.
Making new friends.
I'll bet.
Come on. Let's go.
One brief moment.
In 25 seconds, come over
and insist I must leave immediately.
What? Jane...
One, two, three.
He did it.
- Do it again.
- Some other time.
- How much did you bet?
- 50.
- 50 large?
- No. 50 cents.
- Jane, let's go. Now.
- I won the trifecta.
- I got a little cash to collect.
- Cool. Go ahead then.
- We have plenty of time.
- Okay.
I'm kidding. Come on.
Let's go.
Cough up.
Thank you.
Bye.
Do I wanna know
what that was about?
Uh, no.
Since when do you know
about horses?
I'm not one to brag.
How'd you do it?
Analyze the form?
Ah, I just picked
the coolest names.
Come on.
Tell me how you won.
- Think about it.
- I hate it when you say that.
How'd they do it?
Kill him?
Baseball bat to the head
most likely.
Oh, God.
Any names spring to mind?
Enemies he may have had?
We're trying to look
into Bill's finances
but we can't find any credit cards
not even a bank account.
No, Bill was funny that way.
He just... didn't trust banks.
Cash only.
Had a safe in his closet.
How long had you known him?
November 6th would've been
4 years.
Was that before or after
he had left horse racing?
Bill didn't leave horse racing.
They suspended him two years ago.
There was a-a pile-up
going into a turn.
They said it was Bill's fault
which it wasn't.
They banned him for a year.
That must have been hard on him.
It was a real dark time.
You know, all Bill ever wanted
to do was ride.
He struggled with his temper.
That's a fact.
Is that why you broke up
with him?
The, uh...
the day he got that job
with Holwell?
We thought we should go out
and celebrate, you know?
Sushi.
Except we got in a fender bender
on the way
and uh..
the other driver he...
he's getting all macho
trying to intimidate Bill.
And Bill just went at him
like a crazy person.
You know, he really hurt the guy.
Broke bones.
And when I tried to stop him
he got mad at me.
And we went home
fought half the night
"and I left the next day."
I'm from an abusive family
so, uh...
I see that coming
and I'm out the door.
You catch the guy's name...
the guy he beat up?
No.
Did you see what kinda car
he was driving?
I don't know. Uh...
Some kinda gold muscle car.
Black stripes, maybe.
When was the last time
you saw Bill?
I never really saw him again
after I left.
He tried to talk to me
but I didn't want to.
When he died, he had a note
for you in his pocket.
A note?
And this.
I shoulda stayed.
I shoulda tried to h-help him.
You do what's right for you, okay?
Guy gets beaten up that bad
maybe he holds a grudge
decides to go back
for round two.
Guy gets beaten that badly
he goes to the ER.
Check admissions
from that night.
Also cross-check DMV records
for gold muscle cars.
Yeah, you got it.
I checked Sutton's apartment.
That safe in the closet's empty.
No money anywhere.
- Almost 20 grand missing.
- 20 grand is motive.
Holwell's running Castor's Folly
in the Montague Pineapple Juice Stakes
this Sunday.
What does that have to do
with anything?
Well, it's a big race.
Big step up for horse and rider.
Rider being Sam Starks.
The apprentice. You think getting
to ride could be motive?
Let's ask her.
Are you sure you just don't wanna
go to play the ponies?
- No playing. Strictly business.
- Sheepdip.
I grew up around horses.
I could come with if you...
Grace, could you check
into that incident
where Sutton got suspended
two years ago?
Thank you.
- Get the hell off my property.
- Whoa, whoa!
What are you doing here anyway?
Easy, Cobb, old buddy.
Is there a problem here?
Yeah, I caught Lockhardt here
sneaking around my stable, spying.
Spying? On your horses?
Like I'd learn something.
I was just being neighborly.
Frank Lockhardt
owner of Ad Astra Stables.
Say, aren't you that cop
that knows about horses?
- Jane.
Yeah, I've been hearing about
that trick all day. Very impressive.
Trick? It's no trick.
I actually listen to the animals.
They're very expressive beasts.
Did you hear that?
Doesn't like your suit.
Well, however you did it
congratulations on your choices.
- Two of them were my horses.
- It only takes one horse, Lockhardt.
- You'll see that on Sunday.
- Really? That donkey?
With a little girl in the saddle?
You sure know
how to pick 'em, Cobb.
Sutton wasn't any good either.
The only person who'd hire him
was Holwell here.
- Take a hike, Frank.
- No disrespect, Cobb.
We need people like you
in the horse business.
I mean, without fools and dreamers
where would we be?
Can't have winners
without losers, right?
Castor's Folly is gonna win
on Sunday. You'll see.
Pride and love of these animals
beats your money
and corporate charts
any day of the week.
- Come on.
- That's enough, gentlemen.
We need to speak with Sam Starks.
Do you know where she is?
We need to speak with her.
Watch it! He'll kick.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Sorry, Mr. Holwell.
I don't know what happens.
It's not your fault.
He's just not ready.
Is that Castor's Folly?
No, it's Pollock's Dream.
It's his twin.
His evil twin.
But we'll fix him, eventually.
Right, Sam?
Yes, Mr. Holwell.
Ms. Starks, I'd like to ask you
some more questions.
Um, I don't know if...
No, go ahead, Sam.
Talk to the lady. I got this.
Twins.
- That's rare, huh?
- Yep.
Temperaments are completely different
but each like their dam
in their own way.
Someday they'll both be winners
like she was.
If this bastard will ever let
a rider on him, that is.
So Frank Lockhardt's wrong
about your horses.
Well, the great thing
about racing is, uh...
the more
they underestimate you
the better the odds are
when you win.
The more money you make.
And win we will.
Mark my words.
It's gotta be expensive though...
the upkeep on a horse
that won't let himself be ridden.
Well, people say I'm an old fool
for keeping Poll around
but screw 'em.
The boys are like mirror images
of each other.
The flaws of one
are the strengths of the other.
Keep 'em together
and they'll rub off on each other.
I've seen it happen.
So this one...
Keeps this one
from going crazy.
And what does this one
bring to the mix?
- Oh, he runs like the north wind.
- Ah.
Hello there.
Uh-huh.
Mr. Jane?
Okay.
Really?
Oh. Oh. Excuse me.
We'll talk again soon.
Okay.
Grace. What's up?
I got the scoop
on that pile-up Sutton caused.
Three jockeys were injured...
one of 'em pretty badly.
Ah, that'd be Barnes.
Yeah. He had
multiple broken bones
and spent almost a month
in the hospital.
Ouch.
With Sutton dead, you're getting
a big break as a jockey.
Must be pretty exciting, huh?
I guess. Sure.
Come on. You had to have known
with Sutton gone
that Holwell would probably
go to you.
You don't understand.
Bill was the closest thing
to a family I've ever had.
I'd give anything
to get him back.
But I can't.
Riding's all I have.
It's all I know.
Must be a lot of pressure
on you.
I can handle it.
Then what are you so afraid of?
- I'm not afraid.
- Mm... are too.
Is somebody threatening you?
We can help.
I'm fine. I don't need help.
Are we done?
Can I go?
Sure.
Tough girl. Scared, though.
-Terrified, even.
- Of what?
Ah, there's the rub.
Of what is she so scared?
And the answer is...
Well, it's a rhetorical question.
I have no idea.
Well, I do have an idea
but I'm not gonna tell you
because that
would be premature.
And I am not gonna amuse you
by demanding to know, so there.
So we're both happy then.
So this could be the guy
that Sutton beat up.
Philip Debolt came through ER
with a broken jaw
and contusions
wouldn't say what happened.
He's got a couple
of disorderly conducts.
Gold muscle car
with black stripes.
Symbol of bullying jerks
the world over.
Nice new rims.
Mechanic's gone for the day.
Open tomorrow at 8:00.
Nice chrome rims
on that Mustang out there.
- You're, uh, Phil, I'm guessing.
- Yep.
Expensive, those rims.
And that bling you got there
must have set you back.
There a problem?
Yeah. Here's the problem.
Man's dead
and 20 grand is missing.
Looks like you and your car
are wearing it.
- Who's dead?
- Well, take a wild guess.
Wait, not... not Bill Sutton.
- He's dead?
- Yeah.
That's what happens when you hit
someone that hard, Phil.
I didn't hit him.
He hit me.
And he broke your jaw
humiliated you
so you went after him
got your revenge.
No, it wasn't like that. I mean
yeah, when I saw the guy
I wanted to beat the hell
out of him, sure.
- You talked to him. When?
- He came to the hospital.
- His girlfriend had left him.
- Wait. He visited you at the hospital?
To get things right with me.
To make amends.
I mean, everything in his life
was screwed up
but he wanted to fix it.
Gave me $18,000.
Said he was gonna live his life
straight from then on.
Hey, look, guys, uh...
don't tell the guys
I got beat up.
Kinda said it was a car accident.
Thanks for your time.
- Workin' late?
- Um, just finishing up.
- Stay a while. Chat.
- Let go of me.
Nobody rides for Holwell, see?
- You ride for him, you don't ride again.
- Let go.
Most riders are smart enough to listen.
Don't be one of the stupid ones.
You don't understand.
I don't have a choice...
Look what happened to Sutton.
You want that to happen to you?
"Let her be, Barnes."
Oh, you're a nasty piece
of work, aren't you?
Ah? I knew that from the moment
I saw you
but I didn't think you'd stoop so low
to threaten young girls.
- I've had enough of you.
- Hang on.
No, no.
Whoa, whoa, that's not fair.
Stop! Drop the weapon.
Put your hands in the air
where I can see 'em!
Huh?
And good thing for you
you're a terrible liar.
It's all about the eye contact.
That close. Huh?
Stop it.
Really? Put it down.
Ellis Barnes has a temper.
Popped twice for assault
got probation. Tough guy.
Hold up.
I've got an idea.
"You don't understand.
I don't have a choice."
"Look what happened to Sutton."
"You want that to happen to you?"
Bill Sutton had his head
bashed in.
Did you have something
to do with that?
This is all a misunderstanding.
I was just saying
Starks should be careful.
Friendly advice.
Friendly advice not to ride
for Cobb Holwell.
Why would you care
about that?
I have many interests...
some large, some small.
One of which is hating
Bill Sutton.
We know he put you under
at that race, Mr. Barnes.
- Ended your career.
- He did it on purpose.
I know he did.
Somebody did that to me
you know what I'd do?
I'd kill him.
Well, that's you.
So is there anything else
or are we done here?
Just one more thing.
Mr. Barnes...
I'm from the California Racing Board.
We contacted the CRB
when we brought you in.
- It's routine.
- I don't understand.
You've been selling inside information
to bettors, Mr. Barnes.
Either that information is genuine
which is a heinous breach
of your contract
or it is false, and you are
simply defrauding people.
Either way
pending a full investigation
- I am obliged to ban you from all state...
- Wait, no, I'm a groom.
- How am I supposed to earn?
- However.
Agent Lisbon has asked me
to exercise some discretion here
based on your willingness
to assist her in this...
murder investigation.
All righty then.
Wait.
I didn't kill Sutton.
All I did is threaten him
and threaten Starks.
Who asked you to do that
Mr. Barnes?
Talking to people is no crime.
Who?
Frank Lockhardt
owner of the Ad Astra Stable.
Grace, where is everybody?
Oh. Somewhere else
doing interesting things.
Okay. Come on. Let's go.
- Go where?
- Come on.
- Wait. Did you okay this with Lisbon?
- I certainly did.
What kinda question
is that, anyway?
It's almost like you don't trust me.
We have to stop by your place
on the way, get a different outfit.
- An outfit for what?
- Uh...
Sam Starks, Grace Van Pelt.
- Grace, this is Sam Starks.
- Hi.
Hello.
Grace used to ride.
She grew up around horses.
Dressage, mostly.
A little jumping.
So let's get her a ride, huh?
- Um... a ride?
- Yeah.
- Um... I don't know.
- Sam...
We're cops.
We're police officers.
Okay.
- There we go. Thank you.
- I guess.
Now we're talking. Have fun.
- Hi.
- This is Castor's Folly.
Be safe.
Look, I'm a businessman.
Horses are nothing
but a hobby for me.
Right.
- You're a developer.
- Commercial, mostly.
You wanna get your hands
on Cobb Holwell's stable.
I wanna beat him, sure.
I like winning races
as much as the next man.
Not your hobby.
Your business.
You wanna develop
the Redwood Downs complex.
Holwell has his own stable there
and he won't sell to you.
Well, there was some discussion
about developing Redwood Downs
but nothing concrete.
It's just talk.
Talk that could lead
to millions in revenues.
But first you'd need Holwell's stable.
So?
So you'd like seeing Holwell
outta business.
That's why you paid Ellis Barnes
to stop jockeys riding for him.
Let's say Barnes told jockeys
that if they ride for Holwell
that means they won't ride
for me.
So what? It's the truth.
No law's been broken.
Bill Sutton was responsible
for the accident
that crippled Barnes.
Did you know that?
Barnes was angry about it.
Very angry.
Now you sent a very angry man to threaten
the person he was angry with.
How'd you think
that would turn out?
I think I want my attorney.
That was fun.
What horse is that?
Well, too bad you're so tall
'cause Holwell could use
a second jockey
for Pollock's Dream here.
He's ready to be ridden.
I thought he was the crazy one.
Oh, no, no, he's just...
He's just a little misunderstood.
- He seems like a sweetie.
- Isn't he?
Why don't you hop on?
Oh, I don't know.
Oh, I know horses
and he is 100% safe.
- Look at that. See?
- Yeah?
He's nodding. Jump on.
Oh, I don't know.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Ready and lift.
Okay.
Huh? See? Look at that.
What did I say?
Hey! Get off that horse!
- Are you trying to get yourself killed?
- I'm sorry, Sam. I didn't know.
Relax, Sam.
Poll was telling me he was ready.
I was just proving that Holwell
was right to believe in his horse.
There's no need to thank me.
Thank you?
You trying to get me fired
the day before my big race?
- Yeah. Thanks.
- Sam, I'm sorry...
Mr. Holwell is gonna be so mad
when he hears.
- Please... you have to leave now.
- Okay.
See you, pal.
See you, Pollock's Dream.
- Bye.
- What was that all about?
Clarity, Grace. Clarity.
- Hello, Lisbon.
- Where have you been?
Oh, horseback riding
with Grace.
Oh, that's nice. We've been trying to get
confessions outta Lockhardt and Barnes.
- And how's that going for you?
- "It's not."
Oh, well, surprise.
You can set him free.
Because?
Because I come bearing
a practical and speedy solution
for all your crime detection problems.
- Really?
- Really and truly.
We are off to the races.
Hey!
"Final results from our race
in fifth division"
"but first, Eddie Moon in second,
coming in third was Kindly Dilemma"
"followed by Gift for Mary
and Fortune's Favor."
"Horses for our final race
are now in the paddock area."
Everybody in position?
I'm here.
- "Van Pelt?"
- Here.
"Cho?"
- Anybody got eyes on Jane?
Come on, people.
"Your attention, please."
"The horses are beginning to file onto
the track for the final race of the day."
"The $200,000 Montague Pineapple
Juice Stakes at six and a half furlongs."
Wait a minute. I got him.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey.
This is the guy.
One, two, three.
- This guy knows his horses.
- "Next."
Next.
- Hmm. After you.
- Oh, okay.
10 large on Castor's Folly to win.
Castor's Folly, $10,000.
Castor's Folly.
100 to 1.
Next.
Castor's Folly.
Now don't let him have his head
in the early turns.
He'll wanna get out fast
but don't let him.
Okay.
I know you're behind
that police harassment, Holwell.
You might've had your fun
yesterday
but I'm gonna own
your stable tomorrow.
Well, that's unless he wins today.
What?
Well, if he wins today
then, uh...
he makes enough money
to pay off all his debts.
He's got exactly zero chance
of winning.
- It's 100 to 1.
- I know, great odds, isn't it?
- I got $10,000 on him to win.
- What?
You're a fool. But hey...
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Did you really bet
on Castor's Folly?
Of course I did.
I mean, he's gonna win, isn't he?
What's wrong?
A bet that big
will shorten the odds.
I'll win less money.
What did you bet?
- Every penny I have.
- Well, that's confident.
Desperate.
"And the horses are all going
into the gate..."
Well... not to worry.
He's a cinch.
I can guarantee it.
- Is that right?
- Mm-Hmm.
- How's that?
- A little switcheroo of the horsies.
- What do you mean?
- Castor's Folly and Pollock's Dream...
I switched them in their stalls.
- Don't joke. It's not funny.
- I know you don't think Polly's ready
but I'm telling you, he is
and I know horses.
And you said yourself,
Pollock's Dream is the faster horse.
- Tell me you're not serious.
- They look exactly alike.
Even if the steward
suspected anything
you would've been so surprised
they would have thought
it was an honest mistake.
But they didn't.
So my plan has worked perfectly.
"And they're off.
It's Musketeer's Cat in the lead"
"Calm Thunder in second
Temper's Twilight in third"
"Papa Gene in fourth.
Sheba's Ghost is slow to get going..."
You meddling ass!
I already switched the horses.
You switched them back!
That's how Sutton
ended up dead, isn't it?
He refused to go along
with your plan so you killed him.
And you coerced that poor girl
into taking his place.
You son of a bitch.
That works as a confession, doesn't it?
"Now it's Musketeer's Cat in first."
"Calm Thunder and Temper's Twilight
in third by the rail."
"Sheba's Ghost going up fourth."
"Neck and neck with Papa Gene
on the outside"
"alongside Castor's Folly."
"Coming into the turn
it's Calm Thunder."
"Musketeer's Cat in the lead."
"Then Temper's Twilight
is falling back in fifth."
"Castor's Folly's on
the outside surging ahead."
"Then Ocean Strider pulling up
to seventh. Lucky Boy trailing."
"Rounding turn number two,
it's Musketeer's Cat in the lead"
"and Calm Thunder in second.
Castor's Folly's coming in fast"
"on the outside running upon
Temper's Twilight."
No!
"They're bunched up coming
into the back stretch."
"It's Musketeer's Cat,
and Castor's Folly"
"passing Calm Thunder
for second place."
"Papa Gene is trying to stay in it.
Sheba's Ghost is holding in fifth."
"Four lengths back, it's
Ocean Strider and Lucky Boy."
"Coming into turn three
it's Musketeer's Cat"
"by a length and a half. Castor's Folly
down the center chasing in second."
"Calm Thunder is holding off
Papa Gene at the rail."
"Sheba's Ghost is still running
in fifth."
"Lucky Boy's making a run
at Ocean Strider."
"In first, Musketeer's Cat's in trouble
as Castor's Folly picks up speed."
"Calm Thunder's trying to stay
in it. Papa Gene's falling back."
"Out of turn four,
it's Musketeer's Cat by a length."
"Castor's Folly, second... Calm Thunder."
"Castor's Folly closing in fast
on Musketeer's Cat"
"as they head
down to the wire."
"Musketeer's Cat by half a length.
Castor's Folly and Calm Thunder."
"Musketeer's Cat
then Castor's Folly."
"It's neck and neck.
Musketeer's Cat Springs for the finish."
"Castor's Folly
trying to take the lead."
"Musketeer's Cat switching hard.
Castor's Folly's right there..."
"Pushing ahead is Castor's Folly."
"Castor's Folly takes the lead."
"Castor's Folly wins by a nose."
"Castor's Folly takes
first place."
"Musketeer's Cat in second
Calm Thunder in third"
"and Papa Gene, Sheba's Ghost
Temper's Twilight..."
Mr. Holwell, you're under arrest
for the murder of Bill Sutton.
But you switched the horses.
Uh, I just said that.
I didn't really.
Congratulations.
Your ringer won.
- Murder weapon?
- Yeah.
Lug wrench from Holwell's truck...
Sutton's D.N.A. is all over it.
That and Sam Stark's testimony
will put Holwell away for good.
He told her straight out
that he killed Sutton
to get her to cooperate
with his scheme.
Said that she'd never ride again
or end up dead if she talked.
She was young and naive enough
to believe it.
I still don't get the scheme.
Why didn't Holwell just run
the fast horse?
Well, the odds are no good
on a fast horse.
Everybody bets on him.
It's pennies on the dollar.
Yeah, you run the slow horse
to get the long odds
and then you run the fast horse
to win the money.
But how did he switch the horses?
Don't they check for that?
Well, Holwell gave the fast one
a lip tattoo to match the slow one
so the stewards
couldn't tell them apart.
Ms. Lecure.
I asked evidence
to release this.
Mr. Sutton wanted you to have it
and I think you should.
You know, I think
we would've been okay.
I mean, if we had... time.
I think we would have.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Fool to herself, that girl.
It was never gonna work.
Don't be so cynical.
Oh, you did let Sam Starks go,
didn't you?
She was a mere tool
an innocent pawn.
Semi-innocent, but, yeah
she's free and clear.
She'll be riding
at Santa Anita next week.
Excellent, and Holwell will soon be
riding a bunk in San Quentin.
Well, I vote whoever won
at the track pays for pizza.
The results were thrown out.
Jane didn't win anything.
Nah, he's still got the money
from the trifecta...
the one, two, three.
Well, uh, not so much.
It cost a lot to, uh, win that.
I had to cover
every 3-way combination
of every horse in the race.
Cost me $5,000
and I only won $486.
Wait a minute.
So... you can't read horses?
Of course not.
But it's always a good idea
to seem like you know
what you're talking about.
Fosters trust.
So that means you put Grace
on a potentially wild horse
with no idea what could happen?
Well, I had an idea
that Holwell was putting a burr
under the saddle.
Very old school trick.
Very old school. That's why
I had Grace ride bareback...
to see if I was right
and I was.
You took a terrible chance.
Well, I figured the odds
were 70-30.
I was right.
I wouldn't call that terrible.
A betting man'd call that risky
but certainly not terrible.
Well...
So... pizza.
Nope.